

PHONE 206-406-5108



EMAIL tyler.chinn2@gmail.com



ADDRESS Seattle, WA



LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/tyler-chinn



GITHUB tylerchi1000

EDUCATION

Masters in Data Analytics

Colorado State University Global Campus - Salida, CO Expected Graduation 2023

Bachelor of Science in Materials Science and Engineering

University of Washington - Seattle, WA 2018

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

- SQL (SQL Server)
- Tableau
- Power BI
- Python (PandasScikit-learn, Keras, Matplotlib)
- Git
- Excel
- SAS
- Alteryx (Core Certified)

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Critical Thinking
- Data Cleaning & Preparation
- Data Analysis & Exploration
- Statistical Knowledge
- Creating Data Visualizations
- Creating Dashboards & Reports
- Problem Solving
- Writing Reports
- Project Management
- Data Warehousing
- Research

Tyler Scott Chinn

DATA ANALYST

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and teamwork-oriented Data Analyst with a hunger for challenges and passion for helping businesses succeed. Possesses a Masters in Data Analytics, with strong technical skills; rooted in substantial training as a data analyst. A people-first quick learner and problem solver with an inner drive to create value realized through significant experience across business analysis. Possess strong Documentation skill, good understanding of the principles of Data warehousing, Fact Tables, Dimension Tables etc. Proficient in relational Data modeling, Dimensional data modeling, logical/Physical Design, ER Diagrams and OLTP and OLAP System Study and Analysis as well as Enterprise Information Management and Architecture technologies including Information Lifecycle, Master Data Management and Business Intelligence. Excellent Communication, interpersonal, analytical skills and strong ability to perform in a team as well as individually. Able to synthesize quantitative information and interact effectively with colleagues and clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Reliability Engineering Technician

Microsoft Xbox Team (Contact Through Cascade Engineering Services) - Redmond, WA | October 2019 - October 2020

- Led the qualification of suppliers for the Xbox Series X and Xbox Series S based on product lifecycle criteria.
- Carried out accelerated environmental and mechanical stress testing to ascertain the product's lifespan.
- Created executive dashboards for project progress and performance metrics, saving 10 hours per week.
- Streamlined report generation for management and reliability engineers, including predicted field life and inventory for several hundred high-impact prototypes.

Quality Assurance

Talking Rain - Preston, WA | May 2019 - September 2019

- Managed quality control paperwork and reported inspection test data to ensure regulatory compliance.
- Monitored crucial control points and verified procedures using electronic inspection equipment.
- Took corrective steps to address the production issue, saving one day's worth of production at the factory.
- Used statistical process control software to analyze data and recommend changes to the manufacturing process.

Undergraduate Researcher

UW GEMSEC Research Group - Seattle, WA | June 2017 - June 2018

- Carried out peptide assembly control research with an emphasis on creating medical device products.
- generated reports and conducted data analysis for the interdisciplinary lab group.
- Regularly updated standard operating procedures for ongoing lab experiments.
- Designed an assembly diagram for the formation of material on a graphite surface.
- Collected atomic force microscopy data from samples and processed surface data for categorization.